<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tech Posts on James O'Toole</title><link>https://www.james-o.tools/tech_post/</link><description>Recent content in Tech Posts on James O'Toole</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 17:37:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.james-o.tools/tech_post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Reports Writer Press Release</title><link>https://www.james-o.tools/tech_post/reports-writer-pr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:58:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.james-o.tools/tech_post/reports-writer-pr/</guid><description>Press Release Reports Writer Reports Writer is a new and exciting artificial intelligence technology that assists teachers in writing end of year reports for their students. It is a web application that allows teachers to create a spreadsheet of their students, and then generate a report for each student. The software is much more powerful than existing comment bank tools, which often sound robotic or lack sentence structure and flow.</description></item><item><title>The Learning Line Follower</title><link>https://www.james-o.tools/tech_post/arduino-markov/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 17:51:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.james-o.tools/tech_post/arduino-markov/</guid><description>Be warned, this tale is a tragedy.
For Christmas, my father bought me an Arduino robot kit with 4 wheels some eyes and ears. It came with light (and sonar) sensors. I decided to conduct supervised learning with a Markov chain model. Two front light sensor point vertically down, reading the grounds ability to reflect infrared light. The kit came with black tape to lay on the floor. I aimed to teach the robot to follow the line, programming it to remember 1KB: a weighted guess at a set of movements given the last two things it saw (input reads).</description></item></channel></rss>